JEAN-CHARLES NOIROT FERRAND

SUMMARY_

I am a M.S. Student in the School of Computer, Data, and Information Sciences at the University of Wisconsin-Madison. I am a research assistant in the MadS&P research group and advised by Prof. Patrick McDaniel. My research interests are centered around building more secure and trustworthy Machine Learning models. More specifically, my interests focus on foundation models and how they can securely interact with systems.

EDUCATION _

M.S. in Computer Sciences | University of Wisconsin-Madison
• Advisor: Dr. Patrick McDaniel

Sep 2023 - Present

- B.S. and M.S. in General Engineering | Ecole Centrale de Lyon
 Multidisciplinary studies : Maths, Physics, Computer Science, Fluid Mechanics, Electrical Engineering, Economics, Management, etc.
- Specialization in Computer Sciences and Mathematics.

B.S. Mathematics and applications | Claude Bernard Lyon 1 University
• Double degree with Ecole Centrale de Lyon.

Sep 2021 - August 2022

Classe préparatoires aux grandes écoles | Lycée Marcelin Berthelot

Sep 2019 - July 2021

- 2-year intensive program preparing for the national competitive exams for entry to the top French Engineering Schools.
- Mathematics and Physics cursus, highest honors.

Experience _

Research Assistant | University of Wisconsin-Madison

August 2023 - Present

Madison Security and Privacy Research Group (MadS&P)

Research Intern | Ecole Centrale de Lyon

May 2023 - July 2023

Laboratoire d'InfoRmatique en Image et Systèmes d'information (LIRIS)

Publications _

Workshops/Journals

 Kunyang Li, Kyle Domico, Jean-Charles Noirot Ferrand, Patrick McDaniel. "The Efficacy of Transformer-based Adversarial Attacks in Security Domains". In Workshop on Artificial Intelligence for Cyber (MILCOM 2023). 2023. URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.11597

Projects ___

Research Project: Procedural content generation | Machine Learning

2022-2023

Ecole Centrale de Lyon

- Review of the state-of-the-art procedural content generation: machine learning models such as autoencoders, generative adversarial networks, LSTM, etc.
- Creation and exploitation of a model to generate images using a music and its affect representation.

Study Project: Developing an application for the game Blokus

2022-2023

- Ecole Centrale de Lyon
- Development of an application in C# allowing to play Blokus with players or AI with different difficulties.
- Selected for the school's best study project prize (Francis Leboeuf prize) out of 90 study projects.

Professional Activities _

External Reviewer

- IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (S&P) 2024
- ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS) 2024

Departmental Service

Mentor for new CS Graduate Students - 2024